Emil Haines

www.linkedin.com/in/emilhaines/ www.github.com/emilhaines emilhaines.github.io/

A highly self-motivated PhD student with over three years experience working for international particle physics experiments. Proficient in software development and data analysis using Python and C++, with experience using modern deep learning techniques and frameworks. Hoping to transfer the skills I have acquired in research to a machine learning role within industry.

EXPERIENCE

ATLAS Experiment, CERN

PhD Researcher May 2021 - present

- Qualified author for ATLAS, a leading, international particle physics experiment based at CERN
- Developing and maintaining an analysis framework (C++ and Python), version controlled with git, incorporating signal selection algorithms for the study of exotic decays of the Higgs Boson to long-lived particles
- Experience analysing petabyte-scale datasets produced via particle collisions at the Large Hadron Collider and interpreting results using advanced statistical techniques
- Graph neural networks for classification; algorithm development and performance optimisation (Pytorch)
- Completed a one year attachment at CERN (Oct. 2021 Sep. 2022), during which I undertook shifts as an on-call expert and regularly presented research to fellow students and academics
- Contributions due to be published in high impact physics journals

Graphcore

Silicon Engineer Intern July - Sep. 2019

- o 10 week paid internship in the Silicon Verification team on data analytics and visualisation
- o Presented work to the CEO, CTO and VPs of the company, as well as fellow interns

UCL

Post Graduate Teaching Assistant

Oct. 2020 - May 2021, Jan. 2024 - present

Email: emilhaines@hotmail.co.uk

Mobile: +447905567584

- \circ Responsibilities: running problem classes for \sim 20 students; assisting in teaching during demonstration sessions; marking and providing feedback on coursework
- Courses: (3rd year) Practical Machine Learning for Physicists, Nuclear and Particle Physics, (1st year) Practical Physics and Computing

EDUCATION

\mathbf{UCL}

PhD in Particle Physics

Oct. 2020 - present

- \circ STFC funded research project working on the detection of new particles as a member of the ATLAS experiment
- Participated in postgraduate courses in Machine Learning for Big Data, to further my practical understanding of modern machine learning techniques and database technologies, and Statistical Analysis

University of Bristol

MSci in Physics

Sep. 2016 - June 2020

- o Graduated with first class honours, with an overall mark of 77%
- Awarded commendation for master's project entitled 'Deep Learning for event classification at LUX-ZEPLIN', for which I developed a convolutional autoencoder for detecting waveforms in time-series data (**Tensorflow**)
- Consistently achieved high marks in computational and mathematical units, including: 91 in Methods of Theoretical Physics, 84 in Advanced Quantum Physics and 83 in Quantum Information Theory and Computational Physics

OTHER EXPERIENCE AND INTERESTS

- Undertook part-time roles during my undergraduate degree including: teaching Maths, English and Science to primary, GCSE and A-level students and working in hospitality at the Clifton Pavilion in Bristol Zoo
- Enjoy playing football, running, volunteering at music festivals and am currently teaching myself to play drums